Guide to the Causeries du Lundi Records 1880-2017 (bulk 1880-1974) MS 104
New-York Historical Society
Causeries du Lundi records
1880-2017 (bulk 1880-1974)
New-York Historical Society
Causeries du Lundi
MS 104
8.34 Linear feet (20 boxes)
This collection includes member and meeting information of the women's writing group, Causeries du Lundi, founded in 1880 and still active today. Members of this group write and present their essays at meetings, gathering the first Monday of every month in the winter.
Arrangement
The collection is organized in eight series:
Series I.
Rules of Government / Governance and Incorporation, 1922-2011
Series II.
President's books, 1926-1979
Series III.
Anniversary books, 1890-1955, 2005
Series IV.
Annual reports, 1897-1901
Series V.
Minutes, 1880-1974, 2010-2011, 2013
Series VI.
Members' Essays, 1887-2017
Series VII.
Invitations, 1930-1980
Series VIII.
Miscellaneous, circa 1989-2012
Historical Note
The Causeries du Lundi is one the oldest women's literary societies in the U.S. still active today. Elizabeth Hamilton Collum, the granddaughter of Alexander Hamilton, founded the group in 1880 (Anniversary Book, 1930). Collum believed in a "better future for American women than a life of frivolity" and encouraged members to own and express opinions outside of home and social duties and document their interests in art, literature and scholarly culture.
Today, the group meets at a member's home on the first Monday of every winter month. Generally, only one paper per meeting is read, either by the author or another member. As many members come from prominent New York families, the papers provide insight into their family histories as well as old New York, while topics most often include ancestry, art, travel or historical subjects. Causeries du Lundi incorporated in 2008 and is now known as Causeries du Lundi 1880, Inc.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers.
Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donations of the Causeries du Lundi, 1983, 1990, 1992, 1994, 1996, and 2018 (accession no. MS2018.048).
Related Materials
Further material about the Causeries du Lundi may be found in the Erving-King Papers at the New-York Historical Society.
Scope and Contents
The Causeries du Lundi records are arranged in seven series: President's books, Anniversary books, Annual Reports, Minutes, Member's Essays and Invitations. The bulk of the records are from 1880 to 1974. The majority of the collection consists of the essays written by Causerie members.
The collection documents the founding and administration of the group, its membership, and papers presented by the Causeries du Lundi. The Rules of Government state protocol and procedures of joining and maintaining membership in the Causeries du Lundi.The President's Books detail membership listings, addresses, schedules, and paper topics. Anniversary books were published in celebration of the passing of the years and provide history of the organization and its members. Annual reports and Minutes detail meeting and hostess information, with synopses of presented papers and ensuing discussion, as well as treasury reports. Member files are arranged alphabetically and contain the essays of the members. Some files may also contain clippings, comments and correspondence relating to the essays.
The Causeries du Lundi records contain many essays by women of prominent New York backgrounds with last names such as Lefferts, Peabody, Roosevelt, Delano, Erving, Pierrepont and Parsons, to name a few. One paper of historical interest was submitted by Mrs. Edward Curtis, whose husband performed Abraham Lincoln's autopsy. She included an article written by her husband in 1926 about the event.
Book clubs (Discussion groups) -- New York (State) -- New York; Clubs -- New York (State) -- New York.; Societies -- New York (State) -- New York.; Women -- Societies and clubs; Causeries du Lundi
- Series I. Rules of Government / Governance and Incorporation, 1922-2011; 18148
  Scope and Contents
  This series includes printed material detailing the protocol of membership and governing committees in the Causeries du Lundi.
  - Rules of Government, 1922, 1947, 1970, 2010; 18149 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Rules of Governance drafts, 2010-2011 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Incorporation, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series II. President's books, 1926-1979; 18145
  President's books contain membership information as well as meeting schedules, including the hostess and paper topic lists.
  - President's Books, 1926-1944; 18147 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - President's Books, 1944-1979; 18146 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Series III. Anniversary books, 1890-1955, 2005; 18139
  This series contains printed books celebrating the anniversaries of and detailing the history of the organization and its members.
  - Anniversary Book, 1890; 18144 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Anniversary Book, 1900; 18143 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Anniversary Book, 1912; 18142 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Anniversary Book, 1930; 18141 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Anniversary Book, 1955; 18140 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "A Memoir: Biographical Notes of Members of the Causeries du Lundi", 2005 October 3 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    Compiled for Contributing Members on the 125th Anniversary of Causeris du Lundi, April 12, 1880.
  - "Cocoa, Tea, and the Causeries: Recipes for Intellectual Moments", 2005 October 3 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    Traditional Causeries recipes compiled in honor of the 125th Anniversary of the Causeries du Lundi, April 18, 1880 - October 3, 2005.
- Series IV. Annual reports, 1897-1901; 18133
  Annual reports contain meeting and budget information. After 1901, annual reports are kept with the meeting minutes.
  - Annual Report, 1897; 18138 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Annual Report, 1898; 18137 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Annual Report, 1899; 18136 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Annual Report, 1900; 18135 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Annual Report, 1901; 18134 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Series V. Minutes, 1880-1974, 2010-2011, 2013; 18101
  Minutes detail meeting and hostess information, with synopses of presented papers and ensuing discussion, as well as the group's treasury reports. Book numbers are taken from the cover of notebook or binder of the minutes. Many have been removed from their binder for preservation purposes, but a representative sample of the binders is available at the end of the series.
  - Minutes (Book 1), 1880 Apr.-1886 Jan.; 18132 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Minutes (Book 2), 1886 Feb.-1889 Jan.; 18131 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Minutes (Book 3), 1889 Jan.-1891 Dec.; 18130 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Minutes (Book 4), 1892 Jan.-1894 May; 18129 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Minutes (Book 5), 1894 Nov.-1896 Apr.; 18128 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Minutes (Book 6), 1896 Nov.-1900 Feb.; 18127 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Minutes (Book 7), 1900 Mar.-1902 Mar.; 18126 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Minutes (Book 8), 1902 Nov.-1905 Jan.; 18125 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Minutes (Book 9), 1905 Feb.-1907 Apr.; 18124 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Minutes (Book 10), 1907 Nov.-1909 Apr.; 18123 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Minutes (Book 10A), 1910 Nov.-1911 Apr.; 18122 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Minutes (Book 11), 1909 Nov.-1912 Apr.; 18121 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Minutes (Book 12), 1912 Nov.-1914 Apr.; 18120 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Minutes (Book 13), 1914 Dec.-1917 Apr.; 18119 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Minutes (Book 14), 1917 Dec.-1920 Apr.; 18118 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Minutes (Book 15), 1920 Dec.-1926 Apr.; 18117 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Minutes (Book 16), 1926 Dec.-1929 Apr.; 18116 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Minutes (Book 17), 1929 Dec.-1933 Apr.; 18115 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Minutes (Book 18), 1933 Dec.-1934 Apr.; 18114 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Minutes (Book 19), 1934 Dec.-1940 Apr.; 18113 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1936 Dec.-1941 Nov.; 18112 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Minutes (Book 20), 1940 Nov.-1941 Apr.; 18111 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Minutes (Book 21), 1941 Dec.-1944 Apr.; 18110 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Minutes (Book 22), 1944 May-1952 Apr.; 18109 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Minutes (Book 23), 1952 Apr.-1957 Mar.; 18108 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1957 Apr.-1959 Apr.; 18107 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1959 Nov.-1963 Apr.; 18106 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1963 Nov.-1967 May; 18105 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1967 Dec.-1970 Apr.; 18104 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1970 Apr.-1974 Jan.; 18103 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 2010-2011, 2013 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - [Minute Book], undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Folder marked "Causeries du Lundi / Minute Book" containing photocopied lists of meeting dates and papers read, 1880s-1950s.
  - Representative sample of Minutes binder [empty], 1934-1940; 18102 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Series VI. Members' Essays, 1887-2017; 17944
  This series contains members' essay files with corresponding dates. There is a chronological list of all papers at the beginning of the series. Most papers are 10-30 pages in length, most having been transcribed and typewritten and usually pertain to art, ancestral or historical topics. Some files contain clippings and other miscellaneous notes. If there are more than four papers in a file, the range of dates is given. Member's files are arranged alphabetically and are arranged as their names appear in their papers.
  - Chronological list of papers, undated; 18100 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Andrews, Mrs. Wolcott Erskine, 1975, 1977, 1980; 18098 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Aiken, Mrs. William Appleton, 1967; 18097 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Barker, Mrs. Thompson, 1959, 1964, 1968, 1971; 18096 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Bartlett, Mrs. Philip, 1961-1994; 18095 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Bartol, Mrs. Henry (Hester G.), 1917-1956; 18094 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Bateson, Mrs. E. Farrar (Rosina O.), 1954, 1959, 1969; 18093 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Benjamin, Mrs. William Massena, 1947, 1952, undated; 18092 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Berry, Mrs. Frank, 1963, 1967, undated; 18091 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Bielenstein, Mrs. Hans (Gabrielle Maupin), 1983, 1985, 1988, 1995, 2001; 18090 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Boardman, Mrs. Christina F., 1942-1967; 18089 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Bregman, Mrs. Martin (Cornelia Sharpe), 1998; 52688 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Brown, Caroline L., 2012; 52692 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Bruce, Louise, 2005-2006; 52693 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Buckley, Mrs. Julian, 1964, 1986; 18088 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Cammann, Mrs. H. Schuyler (Katherine), 1928, 1930, 1965, undated; 18087 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Canfield, Mrs. George, 1927, 1930, 1936; 18086 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Cason, Angela, 2011; 52690 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Cheney, Miss Barbara, 1932-1970; 18085 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Cheney, Mrs. George, 1927, 1938; 18084 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Clarkson, Mrs. B., 1934; 18083 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Conn, Gloria J., 1993; 18082 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Cox, Mrs. Thomas Riggs (Marian Buckley), 1963, 1965, 1968, 1971; 18081 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Crocker, Mrs. George (Elizabeth), 1935; 18080 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Curtis, Miss Constance, 1939; 18079 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Curtis, Mrs. Edward (Augusta L.), 1907, 1912, 1926; 18078 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Dahlgren, Miss Olga, 1947-1964; 18077 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Danon, Pamela Tiffin, 1991; 18076 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Dean, Virginia, 2013, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - de Forest, Mrs. Henry W., 1947; 18075 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Delafield, Mrs. Joseph L. (Mary R.), 1948, 1953; 18074 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Dexter, G. M., 1921; 18073 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Downing, Miss Alys M., 1945-1967; 18072 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Downing, Mrs. Augustus, 1937-1962; 18071 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Drexel, Mrs. Joseph (Lucy Wharton), 1887; 18070 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Edey, Mrs. Alfred, 1935, 1944; 18069 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Ely, Mrs. W. Page, 1928-1948; 18068 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Erving, Miss Justine Bayard, 1918-1952; 18067 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Ewall, Mrs. Guy, 1994; 18066 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Fabend, Mrs. Firth Haring, 2001; 52683 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Fairchild, Mrs. B. Tappan (Julia Freeman), 1955-1977; 18065 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Fairfax, Eleanor V. R., 1910; 18064 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Farnum, Mrs. Peter (Louise Kobbe), 1941, 1945, 1949, 1951; 18063 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Flagg, Mrs. Ernest, 1938-1969; 18062 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Fooshee, Wynne Byard, 1987, undated; 18061 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Forsyth, Mrs. William (Agnes M.), 1984, 1989, undated; 18060 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Fraser, Linda, 2015-2016 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Frey, Mrs. Guernsey (Josephine W.), 1958, 1961; 18059 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Gade, Mrs. John A., 1955; 18058 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Geer, Mrs. William Montague Jr. (Edith), 1927; 18057 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Geer, Mrs. J. Roosevelt (Dorothy), 1941-1961; 18056 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Geer, Mrs. Langdon, 1937, undated; 18055 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Glass, Martha, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Grant, Miss Edna, 1966; 18054 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Grant, Miss Julia M., 1949-1961; 18053 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Griffis, Martha Hughes, 1978; 18052 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Grimes, Miss Frances, 1946, 1950, 1954; 18051 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Hand, Mrs. Augustus, 1931-1956; 18050 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Hatch, Mrs. Sinclair (Laura Lea), 1961, 1964, 1970, undated; 18049 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Harter, Mrs., 1935; 18048 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Hellman, Mrs. Geoffrey (Katherine), 1971-1979; 18047 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Henry, Mrs. Seton (Josephine W. Drexel), 1942-1958; 18046 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Herrick, Mrs. G. P., 1941; 18045 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Heyniger, Mrs. C. Lambery, 1928, 1935, 1939, 1942; 18044 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Hoff, Mrs. Arthur B., 1974, 1977, 1980; 18043 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Hoge, Mrs., 1977; 18042 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Hoogenboom, Edith S., [2012?] (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Hoppin, S.C.W., 1927; 18041 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Howells, Sarah Lord, 1893; 18040 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Humphrey, Mrs. Theodore, 1936, 1940, 1953; 18039 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Huntington, Miss Catherine, 1962; 18038 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Huntington, Mrs. Francis (Susan L.), 1933, undated; 18037 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Hutchins, Mrs. Robert S. (Evelyn), 1968-1984; 18036 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Hutchinson, Mrs. M. (Martha), 1935; 18035 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Janeway, Mrs. John H., 1910-1931; 18034 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Jarrett, Mrs. Edwin, 1949, 1952; 18033 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Kimmelman, Elbrun, 2000-2012, 2015, 2017, undated; 52686 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - King, Mrs. Augustus, 1939, 1945, 1949; 18032 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Lambert, Mrs. Adrian, 1945; 18031 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Lee, Mrs. Elliott Hugh, 1959, 1964, 1968; 18030 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Lefferts, Mrs. Barent (Isabella M.), 1935-1955; 18029 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Lefferts, Mrs. Gillett, 1937; 18028 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Lipson, Mrs. Howard, 1970, 1973; 18027 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Lounsberry, Miss Alice, 1939; 18026 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - McClintock, Mrs. John T. (Mary M.), 1972-1989; 18025 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - McCrary, Mrs. Dennis Daughtry (Eugenia), 1986, 1988, 1994; 18024 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - McKay, Renee, 1993; 18023 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - McLean, Mrs. Alan D., 1937; 18022 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Malone, Mrs., 1975; 18021 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Manger, Lynn S., 2009; 52696 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Marrow, Julia O., 1975; 18020 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Marsh, Charlotte Delafield, 1927; 18019 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Masters, Mrs. Francis Robert, 1940, 1948, 1959; 18018 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Meade, Mrs. Richard (Helena Rutherford Ely), 1908-1965; 18017 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Melcher, Mrs. John (Helen), 1938-1968; 18016 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Morgan, Mrs. John Williams, 1955, 1958, 1962; 18015 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Munroe, Mrs. S. C., 1942; 18014 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Myers, Mrs. Joseph Lawrence (Henrietta), 1927, 1932; 18013 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Nagel, Susan, 1999-2012, 2017; 52684 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Nichols, Acosta, 1979, undated; 18012 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Olyphant, Miss Jeannette, 1956, 1959, 1963, 1964; 18011 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Opdycke, Mrs. Leonard E., 1911; 18010 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Ostrander, Mrs., 1928; 18009 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Paine, Mrs. Augustus G. (Francisca Warren), 1939, 1961; 18008 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Paine, Mrs. Hugh E. Jr. (Julia), 1970, 1973; 18007 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Parker, Elinor, 1983, 1986, 1988; 18006 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Parsons, Mrs. Williams (Louise B.), 1976, 1978, 1986; 18005 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Patterson, Mrs. Henry S., undated; 18004 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Peabody, Mrs. George R., 1935; 18003 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Peabody, Mrs. John D., 1945; 18002 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Peabody, Mrs. Robert Swain (Helen Lee), 1944-1972; 18001 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Perdue, Mitzi, 2011-2012, 2014-2015, 2017; 52695 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Piel, Madelaine, 2011; 52689 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Pierce, Mrs. William Curtis (Elizabeth Gay), 1965-1987; 18000 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Platt, Miss Mary Cheney, 1969, 1971, 1977, undated; 17999 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Poindexter, Mrs. George, 1983; 17998 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Porter, Mrs. Frank, 1959, 1965; 17997 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Pruyn, Mrs. John A. (LaVerne), 1972-1991; 17996 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Pulsifer, Mrs. Harold (Susan Nichols), 1931, 1936, 1940, 1943; 17995 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Quaid, Mrs. Hopeton D. Atterbury, 1953, 1957; 17994 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Rawle, Mrs. Henry, undated; 17993 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Richards, Mrs. Charles A. (Henrietta King), 1927, 1940; 17992 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Richards, Cordelia C., 1985; 17991 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Robinson, Mrs. Beverly R., 1963, 1966; 17990 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Rollins, Mrs. Philip Ashton, 1932, 1937, 1941; 17989 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Roosevelt, Kate Shippen, 1920, 1922, 1924; 17988 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Rorimer, Mrs. James (Katherine), 1988, 1990, 1992, 1994; 17987 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Rosasco, Joan T., 2011, 2012; 52691 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Rue, Mrs. Frances J. Jr., 1968, 1982, 1984, 1992; 17986 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Saltus, Mrs. Ralph (Marilyn M.), undated; 52694 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Sargent, Mrs. James C. (Rebecca P. J.), 1974-1995; 17985 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Savage, Mrs. Theodore Fiske (May), 1950-1972; 17984 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Savage, Mrs. William L. (Serena Hand), 1932-1944; 17983 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Schieffelin, Mrs. Schuyler, 1934; 17982 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Seward, Miss Alice, 1911; 17981 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Sherman, Mrs., 1939; 17980 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Shippen, Miss, 1945, undated; 17979 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Shreve, Georgia, 2015-2016 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Simons, Mrs. Minot, undated; 17978 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Slade, Mrs., 1941, 1943, 1946; 17977 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Smith, Mary (Polly) Coxe, 1990, 2001, undated; 17976 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Smith, Mary [same as Mary (Polly) Coxe Smith, above?], 2011 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Smith, Mrs. Mason (Mary A. E.), 1949, 1951, 1955; 17975 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Southworth, Mrs. H., 1966, 1981; 17974 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Spears, Mrs. T. Guthrie Jr. (Susan Savage), 1954-1978; 17973 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Stickney, Mrs. Henry A. (Helen Morgan Frick), 1938, 1941, 1943, 1946; 17972 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Stillman, Mrs. Ernest (Mildred W.), 1943, 1947; 17971 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Stillman, Eugenia, 1985; 17970 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Stryker, Mrs. Lloyd Paul, 1957, 1961; 17969 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Sutcliffe, Mrs. Arthur (Alice Crary), 1927-1951; 17968 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Talbot, Mrs. Arthur, 1930, 1939; 17967 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Thomas, Mrs. J. H., 1944, 1948, 1952; 17966 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Tuckerman, Mrs. Elliot, 1927; 17965 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Tuckerman, Miss E. L., 1922; 17964 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Tuckerman, Miss Jane, 1903-1914; 17963 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Twiss, Mrs., 1967, 1972, 1981; 17962 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Twyeffort, Mrs., 1979, 1982, 1983; 17961 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Unknown authors, 2018, undated; 18099 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Van Antwerp, Gwendolen, 1975; 17960 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Van Rensselaer, Mrs. John King, undated; 17959 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Wagstaff, Miss Mary, 1930-1967; 17958 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Warner, Mrs. Bradford, 1989; 17957 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Warner, Mrs. Wolcott (Eloise), 1995; 17956 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Webber, Martha Rosalie Myer, 1958-1976; 17955 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Weekes, Miss Alice Delano, 1926, 1929, 1933; 17954 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Wightman, Mrs. (Anne), 1943, 1946; 17953 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Wheelock, Mary Jane Victor, 1999; 52687 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Whyte, Mrs. W. Hollingsworth (Jenny Bell), 1974, 1978, 1987, undated; 17952 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Willard, Anne H., 1955; 17951 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Williams, Mrs. I. T. (Edna D.), 1969,1970, 1975; 17950 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Williams, Mrs. Roderick (Dorothea C.), 1978-2003; 17949 (Box 18, Folder 8-9)
  - Woodman, Mrs. Charles, 1957, 1964, undated; 17948 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Woolsey, Alice Bradford, 1932; 17947 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Young, Mrs. Benjamin S., 1940-1972; 17946 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Young, Mrs. Thomas S. (Caroline E.), 1905, 1927; 17945 (Box 19, Folder 4)
- Series VII. Invitations, 1930-1980; 17942
  This series consists of ten printed invitations to Causeries du Lundi meetings.
  - Invitations, 1930-1980; 17943 (Box 19, Folder 5)
- Series VIII. Miscellaneous, circa 1989-2012
  - Membership lists, circa 1989, 2005 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Causeries at New-York Historical Society, circa 1993-2007 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    Documentation of transfer of custody of the Causeries du Lundi Records to the New-York Historical Society.
  - Causeries archives (2 folders), 2011-2012 (Box 20, Folder 5-6)